The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twenty-Third Episode
The Phantom Knight
Now, before I tell you
today's story,
I will summarize the last episode.
One night,
the King was no longer to be found..
...and people thought
that he was dead.
Then Sapphire prepared
to become King.
But during the ceremony
of coronation,
the Queen was deceived
by Grand Duke Duralumin and Nylon
and drank some drugged wine.
Then the situation became serious.
This drug had the effect
of making whoever drinks it say...
everything they think.
The Queen revealed the secret.
In front of various representatives
gathered from all over the world,
she confessed that Sapphire
was a girl.
Therefore, Sapphire and the Queen
were condemned...
...to be locked up in the
coffin tower as punishment.
Today's story tells you
about what happened...
...to the two of them while they were
locked in prison.
Gama! Where is the jailer Gama?
I'm here! I'm coming right away!
- Mother!
- Try to stay calm
Bring out Sapphire and the Queen!
Mother, be careful.
Thank you, Sapphire.
Welcome,
Princess Sapphire and the Queen!
Well, Gama,
I'll leave everything to you.
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
Yes, yes, alright, Captain.
Now we can go.
My God, how gloomy this tower is!
Please, enter!
What is this whistling sound?
It's the wind. If you are afraid
of this simple noise,
- you won't be able to live here.
- Where is our room?
Go up the stairs and you will find her.
- They are bats.
- How creepy!
It's full of beasts here!
We have arrived!
This is your room.
Isn't there a bed in this room?
Bed?
Hey, bring those two beds!
Yes, sir!
Who are they?
They are my entourage!
Give me that jewel
in exchange for the two beds
Oh, no! This is
a dear keepsake of the King.
Hey, then take back
the beds!
Yes, sir!
And then you will sleep
on the cold floor.
- Listen, Gama...
- Sapphire!
- Mother!
- Oh, alright.
- Hey, bring back the beds!
- Yes, sir!
Please, turn on the light.
- Hey, bring the lamps!
- Yes, sir!
Give me that brooch in
exchange for the lamps!
This is too much!
Now stop it! Enough!
- He says he doesn't need them anymore!
- Yes, sir!
Wait! We can't do without them.
Here!
We've been here for three days now.
Sapphire, you're hungry, aren't you?
But you only had
a small breakfast.
Do you want me to prepare dinner for you?
I wish you would,
but I have nothing left.
You took all my jewels!
What do you mean "nothing"?
You still have those gorgeous clothes!
If I give you these clothes,
will you give me others?
Of course I will give you others!
And very beautiful ones, too!
- Mother...!
- Very well.
Mother, what clothes!
It doesn't matter, we don't need
beautiful clothes here anymore.
Dinner is ready! Here you go!
Good heavens! And in exchange
you give us so little to eat?!
I'm fine, but I want
Sapphire to eat more!
Then you will need
many more jewels!
But now I have nothing left!
Aren't you, perhaps,
hiding some?
No! Really,
I have nothing left.
Nothing! You have nothing, huh?
Then you will do the washing
and the Princess will sweep!
What?! You are ordering
my mother to wash...
- Silence!
- Sapphire!
You will have to work a lot
and hard too, if you want to eat!
- You're cheerful, Sapphire.
- Yes! Better to sing than to cry!
And besides, I must say
that singing helps me work!
You're right! It helps
me too, you know?
Damn you!
Don't waste time chattering!
And now let's see where
I can throw this garbage.
Ah, there! I found it!
I'll throw them out of here!
My God, this is Gama's room!
Damn it! If you play another
trick like that on me, I'll kill you!
Forgive me, but I didn't
know it was your room!
Instead of going to dinner, you
will clean the floor! Understood?
Alright, let's see...
Where is the cleaning rag?
Ah, here it is! I found it!
If you sing, you can't
clean well! Give it to me!
Look how it's done!
How dirty this rag is!
But these are my
clothes! Damn you!
Your clothes?! Help!
Come here, so I can strangle you!
Take that! Oh, no!
All my lunch! No!
I'll have to go hungry
and I also have a headache!
You, meanwhile, will go to work
without eating! Go on, get out!
And then, soon, we will see the sun...
Stop it! Stop singing!
Think about grinding
and making good bread!
I will eat it, you damned idiot!
But that's a mouse!
Wait, thief mouse!
My God...!
Give it here!
Listen to me carefully! You will kill
all the mice in this tower!
No! They are God's creatures!
I'm very hungry.
Tomorrow you can eat
my lunch too.
- I'm so happy!
- Good heavens! Why?
Because even if we suffer,
we can be together so much.
If only dad
could be here with us...
You promised not to cry.
- I'm sorry.
- It's not so bad here.
There is no one
plotting against us,
there is no Duralumin
and not even Nylon.
Thank you, Sapphire! When I look at you,
I feel great courage.
Yes...
But I'm so hungry!
Did you come to thank me?
Don't worry!
Look, mother!
They brought us food!
Splendid! Another one!
This is a notice! "From now on,
no one shall speak of Sapphire.
Whoever utters his name will
be whipped a hundred times...
...and will be sentenced to
slavery. Grand Duke Duralumin".
That cursed Duralumin
is ruling like a tyrant!
Right, mother?
I am sure that this
notice is not the only one!
Now that my father and I
are not here, he's hard at work!
How I wish I could get out of here!
What are they doing?
Mother, look!
What is this hole?
How deep it is!
I think it leads to the dungeons.
Be careful, it's very narrow!
I'm out!
How wonderful! Thank you!
Thank you, little mice!
- Sapphire! - Mother, there's an exit
this way!
- Come!
- Now let's get out of this place!
This hole is too small
for me. Escape by yourself.
No! I will never be separated from you!
No, you must escape, Sapphire,
and fight
against our enemies.
Gama is coming!
May I know
what you are whispering?
Nothing! I was only saying
that I'm hungry! So hungry!
Don't tell me stories!
I'm not buying it!
You were planning to escape, huh?
Remember that, if you escape,
I will cut off the Queen's head!
- My God! - What?!
- Duralumin ordered me to!
- Mother!
- Don't worry about me.
Get out of here right now
and go fight!
This is your duty
as Prince of Silverland.
But if they should catch me, you..
Sapphire, what is more important?
My life...
...or the life of so many poor
people who, at this moment,
are suffering
under cruel laws?
- Mother, look!
- Look at those little mice!
My sword and my clothes!
You took them from Gama's room,
right?
Go ahead, whip him!
Listen to me well, everyone!
This man spoke of Sapphire
...and called King Plastic
an "idiot",
therefore he was whipped
...and now he will work as a
slave for the rest of his life!
He will be a slave for his whole life!
Poor boy..!
No! No!
This cursed child
was praising Sapphire!
- What?!
- Sapphire was very kind!
Plastic is an idiot and an imbecile!
Wretched child!
Whip him!
He will not be spared just
because he is a child! Go on!
Oh, my son! He is my only
son! Please, forgive him!
No! No! Go away, or
you will be whipped too!
- Come on, hurry up! Go!
- Wait!
Damn it! And who are you?
I am the phantom knight!
Remember me!
What?! The phantom knight?!
He's a suspicious man! Arrest him!
What are you doing?
Have you given up already?
How dare you challenge me, brat?
You dared to challenge
me I'll make you pay!
Hooray! Hooray!
Boy, cut the rope of the
prisoners with this sword!
Thank you, phantom knight!
Knight, please, will
you show me your face?
No, I cannot do it! Farewell!
Well, I never..! Well, I never!
You look like an idiot!
Are you hungry?
You are a complete idiot!
Get out of the way, Plastic!
What's happening, Nylon?
Well, please listen to me!
Suddenly
a strange guy appeared!
He freed all the prisoners
and let them escape!
A strange guy?!
Yes! He was very strange!
He was three meters tall!
We could have beaten
him, if he hadn't been so tall!
- Extremely tall!
- Don't talk nonsense!
Damn it, there he is!
Is he the strange guy?
Soldiers! Soldiers!
That guy is a scoundrel!
He's near the window!
Attack him from all sides!
Appost yourselves outside the window!
Don't let him escape!
It's just you and me, Duralumin!
How dare he break
my beautiful bookcase?
- Catch him immediately!
Get him!
Remember, arrogant Duralumin: if
you make people suffer again,
the phantom knight will kill you!
Remember it well!
What are you doing? Get him!
What is it, Nylon?
Don't you think his voice
sounds a lot like Sapphire's?
What?! Sapphire?!
Yes!
Let's split into two teams!
One will hunt the knight and
the other goes to the coffin tower...
...to see if Sapphire
is there or not!
Go! The phantom knight...
could be Sapphire...
Nylon has become alarmed and is going
to inspect the coffin tower.
I must hurry back,
or my mother will be in danger!
Gama! Where is Gama? It's Nylon!
- Open the door immediately!
- Yes!
Go away!
Hello, Nylon! Your nose
is getting bigger and bigger! How come?
Damn it!
I was sure it was Sapphire!
I'm sorry if I'm a bit late
Now I'm more relieved
If you were any later,
I would have really worried.
Oh, how sweaty you are..
Good! So Sapphire
was in the Coffin Tower!
Yes! As long as you leave them alive,
we'll have problems!
Let's kill them!
I've already thought of that.
I sent five assassins
to the tower,
with the order to kill them!
By now
they must have already arrived
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP